（阿冈戈化学武器工厂 苏联）
抱歉 忘了敲门
I beg your pardon. I forgot to knock.
别乱动
其他人呢？
我是一个人
I'm alone.
我们谁不是？
Aren't we all?
- 你迟到了 007 - 我得去上厕所
- You're late, 007. - I had to stop in the bathroom.
又准备拯救世界吗？
Ready to save the world again?
你先请 006
After you, 006.
詹姆斯 为英国
James, for England.
为英国 艾力克
For England, Alec.
太容易了
It's too easy.
所有事情一半都是靠运气 詹姆斯
Half of everything is luck, James.
另一半呢？
And the other half?
靠命运
Fate.
- 计时六分钟 - 六分钟 无误
- Set timers: six minutes. - Six minutes, check.
开枪！
Fire!
打烊了 詹姆斯！最后一次！
Closing time, James! Last call!
给我买一品脱
Buy me a pint.
我是巫上校 举起双手出来！
This is Colonel Ourumov! Come out with your hands above your heads!
每个人都知道
How original.
艾力克
Alec?
出来 放下武器慢慢走过来
Move out Throw down your weapon and walk towards me, slowly.
快完成任务 轰掉他们！
Finish the job, James! Blow them all to hell!
给你十秒钟
You have ten seconds.
十…
Ten…
…九…八…
nine… eight…
七…六…
seven… six…
…五…
five…
…四 三 二…
four… three… two…
为英国 詹姆斯！
For England, James!
停火！会打到瓦斯桶
Hold your fire! You'll blow the gas tanks!
给你最后机会 举起手出来…
This is your last chance. Come out with your hands above your…
等等！
Wait!
你赢不了
You can't win.
出来！快！快走！
Get out there! Move! Move it!
不要开火！
Hold your fire!
等等！
Wait!
《007系列之黄金眼》
（九年后）
詹姆斯 你真的有必要开得这么快吗？
James, is it really necessary to drive quite so fast?
比你预想的要经常多了
More often than you'd think.
我也像别的女孩一样爱坐飞车 不过…
I enjoy a spirited ride as much as the next girl, but…
- 那是谁？- 别的女孩
- Who's that? - The next girl.
詹姆斯 别这样！打住！我知道你想干嘛
James, stop this! Stop it! I know what you're doing.
真的？我在干嘛 亲爱的？
Really? What's that, dear?
你只是现你的…
You are just trying to show off the size of your, your…
- 引擎？- 自大狂
- Engine? - Ego.
我们开车寻开心你却来这套心理分析
We're having a pleasant drive and you've got to bring psychology into it.
我奉命来评估你
I was just sent here to evaluate you.
我们还是别想公事了
Let's try and put that behind us, shall we?
女士优先
Ladies first.
- 詹姆斯 我让你停车 - 真的？
- James, I want you to stop this car. - Really?
马上停车！
Stop this car at once!
你看…我完全能遵守女上司的命令
As you can see, I have no problem with female authority.
詹姆斯 你真是无药可救
James, you're incorrigible.
我拿你没辙
What am I going to do with you?
好了 为你的评估干杯好吗？
Well, let's toast your evaluation, shall we?
彻底的评估
A very thorough evaluation.
晚安 邦德先生 欢迎再次光临
晚安 皮耶 你好吗？
好啊 很好 你呢？
女士赢了
Madame wins.
有人下注吗？
Bets, ladies and gentlemen?
没人下注？
No players?
我来
I come.
看来我们兴趣相投 只不过三种
It appears we share the same passions. Three, anyway.
我认为两种
I count two.
开车和玩牌
Motoring and baccarat.
七点 女士赢了
Seven. Madame wins.
希望第三种是你真正的看家本颌
I hope the third is where your real talent lies.
我决不退缩
One rises to meet a challenge.
要牌
女士手上有五点
Madame stands with five.
六点 女士输了
Six. Madame loses.
及时行乐吧
Enjoy it while it lasts.
那是我的座右铭
The very words I live by.
你的座右铭是什么？
And what words do you live by?
见机行事 见好就收
The trick is to quit while you're still ahead.
这本事我可学不来 不如你教我别的
That's one trick I've never learned. Perhaps you'll show me how it's done.
伏特加马丁尼 用摇的 不要搅的
Vodka martini. Shaken, not stirred.
你呢？
And for you?
一样
The same.
你怎么喝？
How do you take it?
不加冰…加柠檬皮…
Straight up, with a twist.
谢谢 先生您是…
Thank you, Mr…
我叫邦德 詹姆斯邦德
The name's Bond. James Bond.
莎妮安娜拓
Xenia Zaragevna Onatopp.
- 安娜拓？- 安娜拓
- Onatopp? - Onatopp.
你是乔治亚人？
Your accent, Georgian?
很好 邦德先生
Very good, Mr. Bond.
- 你去过俄国？- 最近没有
- You've been to Russia? - Not recently.
以前偶尔去一去 快进快出
I used to drop in occasionally. Shoot in and out.
现在大不相同了 一个冒险家乐园
It's very different now, a land of opportunity.
家家车库停着新的法拉利？
with a new Ferrari in every garage?
那倒不是 这车是朋友的
No, not quite. That belongs to a friend.
给你朋友个建议
A tip for your friend:
今年法国车牌是“L”宇开头
The French registration plates for this year's model start with the letter "L."
仿造的也一样
Even the counterfeit ones.
你在交通部
Oh. And what rank do you hold…
当什么差…邦德先生？
with the Motor Vehicles Department, Mr. Bond?
中校
Commander.
- 咱们走吧？- 这位是上将
- Shall we go? - This one is an Admiral.
我比官阶更喜欢女人
I like a woman who enjoys pulling rank.
幸会 邦德先生
Nice to meet you, Mr. Bond.
全是我的荣幸
The pleasure, I'm sure, was all mine.
（曼蒂哥号）
钱班霓开始传送
Transmission begins from Moneypenny.
确认身份 莎妮安娜拓 前苏联战斗机驾驶
Identification confirmed: Onatopp, Xenia. Ex-Soviet fighter pilot.
该嫌犯与圣彼得堡的亚努犯罪组织有联系
Current suspected links to the Janus crime syndicate, St. petersburg.
曼蒂哥号租给亚努的公司
Yacht Manticore is leased to a known Janus corporate front.
M准许你观察安小姐…
M authorizes you to observe Miss Onatopp…
但未获准许不得与她接近
but stipulates no contact without prior approval.
钱班霓 传送完毕 晚安 詹姆斯
End transmission. Moneypenny. Good night, James.
我相信你会“小心行事”
I trust you'll stay "on-a-topp" of things.
莎妮 我不能呼吸了！
Xenia, I can't breathe!
嗯！嗯！
Yes! Yes!
向您致敬 上将！
My respects, Admiral.
欢迎莅临
Delighted to have you aboard, Mademoiselle.
各位女士们先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen…
请上甲板观赏直升机演练
please take your seats on the upper deck for the demonstration of the aircraft.
你们看到的将是
What you are about to see in operation…
欧洲对电子战的答案
is Europe's answer to the electronic battlefield:
第一个”猛虎”直升机原型
The first working prototype of the Tiger helicopter.
不仅使用特殊灵活的“隐形”科技…
Uniquely maneuverable, the Tiger not only uses stealth technology…
…更能防御任何…
it is the only helicopter to be hardened against…
…电子干扰、无线电或…
all forms of electronic interference…
…电磁辐射线的唯一的直升机机种
radio jamming and electromagnetic radiation.
我从你们基地那里的朋友带给你们一个小小的惊喜
I have a small surprise from your friends back at the barracks.
我想我走运了
I think I've gone to heaven.
还没有呢
Not yet.
现在请欢迎驾驶员
Now please welcome the pilots.
贾少校以及白上尉
Lieutenant Commander Bernard Jaubert…
太空武器控制中心 俄国 塞维亚
and Lieutenant Francois Brouse.
选项
Select Mir.
自动绘图投射
Autographic projection.
计算拦截第二测地卫星距离 输入密码
Compute possible intercept with second stage geo-sat two.
安娜？
Anna.
既便是女人投怀送抱他都无法接受
He wouldn't know a woman if one came up and sat on his head.
波洛？
Boris.
- 波洛！- 什么？
- Boris! - What?
我记得我不是登在网路上了吗？
I thought I'd post it on the Internet, no?
- 密码是什么？- 这次我写个简单的
- What's the password? - I made it easy this time.
就连你都能破译 真是笨蛋一个
Even you should be able to break it, borscht for brains.
好吧 给你个提示
All right, all right, I'll give you a hint.
就在你眼前可以打开很大的门
They're right in front of you and can open very large doors.
密码门环 你真讨厌！
You're such a geek.
好棒！我进入了！
Yes, I'm in!
你已经闯入了美国司法部
You've hacked into the U.S. Department of Justice.
知道被追查到的后果吗？
Do you know what will happen if they trace it here?
电脑部主任会把我当天才
The Chief of Computers will call me a genius…
…调找到莫斯科 给我一百万元
move me to Moscow and give me a million bucks hard currency.
才怪
I think not.
不过 美国人很笨 绝对查不到我的
Besides, the Americans are slug-heads. They'll never detect me.
- 你说他们很笨？- 没人敢惹我葛波洛
- You were saying, slug-head? - Nobody screws with Boris Grishenko!
破坏他们！
Spiked them!
快挂断
Come on, Boris, just hang up.
才不！我破坏他们了！
No way! I spiked them!
好啦 密码是什么？
All right, what's the password?
我不告诉你
I'm not going to tell you.
让我猜猜
Okay, let me guess.
不是在我前面吗？
It's not in front of me?
你能坐在上面却不能带走
You sit on it, but you can't take it with you.
我的程式能够拦截任何追踪我的电话
My program seizes the phone line of whoever's tracing me…
干扰数据机 他们无法挂断
and jams their modem so they can't hang up.
现在猎物变成猎人了
Now the hunted becomes the hunter.
（联邦调查局电脑诈欺部）
祝你下次好运
Better luck next time…
笨蛋！
slug-heads!
成功了！
Bang! Gone!
我所向无敌！
I am invincible!
你不是也过瘾吗？
Was it good for you, too?
我去喝咖啡
I'm getting some coffee.
我去抽一支烟
I'm going for a cigarette.
阿凯蒂巫洛莫将车
General Arkady Grigorovich Ourumov…
太空部负责人
head of Space Division.
- 将军 若我知道… - 你应该已经准备就绪
- General, if I'd known… - You'd have been ready.
这是临时战争模拟试验
This is an unscheduled test of the Severnaya facility. War simulation.
我们要试发黄金眼 请报告
We are going to test-fire GoldenEye. Report your status.
两枚卫星 将军
Two operational satellites, sir: Petya and Mischa…
以九十分钟一百公里的速度运行
both in 90-minute earth orbit at 100 kilometers.
很好 这是授权密码
Good. Here is the authorization code.
黄金眼和今天的卫星操作序号
Now, the GoldenEye and today's access numbers for satellite Petya, please.
我在计时
I am timing you.
很好 谢谢你
Good. Thank you, Major.
倒数
On my count.
三…二…一
Three… two… one.
设定目标 塞维亚
Set target: Severnaya.
准备武器
Arm the weapon.
确认！
Check it!
救援最快l9分钟才能来 他们会晚到的
Their best response time is 19 minutes. They'll be late.
没事了 我得清理掉一个人
It's clean. I had to ventilate someone.
- 晚安 钱班霓 - 晚安 詹姆斯
- Good evening, Moneypenny. - Good evening, James.
M在军情室 我带你进去
M will meet you in the situation room. I'm to take you straight in.
我从来没有下班后见过你 真漂亮
I've never seen you after hours, Moneypenny. Lovely.
- 谢谢夸奖 詹姆斯 - 有特别任务吗？
- Thank you, James. - Out on a professional assignment?
要去迷倒众生？
Dressing to kill?
我知道你很失望 007
I know you'll find this crushing, 007…
我不是坐在家里为国际事件祈祷…
but I don't sit at home every night praying for an international incident…
所以我盛装赶来让詹姆斯邦德开眼
so I can run down here all dressed up to impress James Bond.
我跟一位绅士有约 一起去看戏
I was on a date with a gentleman. We went to the theater together.
钱班霓 我好伤心
Moneypenny, I'm devastated.
失去你 我怎么办？
What would I ever do without you?
就我的记忆里 詹姆斯 你从没得到过我
As far as I can remember, James, you've never had me.
有希望才有无限春梦
Hope springs eternal.
你知道 这种行为算是性骚扰
You know, this sort of behavior could qualify as sexual harassment.
真的吗？该怎么罚？
Really? What's the penalty for that?
总有一天你得实现你的讽刺话
Someday you have to make good on your innuendos.
- 你先请 钱班霓 - 不 我坚持…
- After you, Moneypenny. - No, I insist.
还是你先请
You first.
- 你好 007 - 丹诺 什么事？
- Good evening, 007. - Tanner. What's up?
我们截获了一个遇险信号
Sixteen minutes ago, we intercepted a distress call…
来自塞维亚废弃的雷达站
from a supposedly abandoned radar station at Severnaya.
看看卫星拍的照片
Look what the satellite picked up.
我们找到了失踪的“猛虎”直升机
We found a match: your missing Tiger.
在北俄罗斯中部吗？
In the middle of Northern Russia.
你猜的没错 007
It seems your hunch was right, 007.
可惜你的邪恶的女上司不让你玩
It's too bad the evil Queen of Numbers wouldn't let you play it.
- 你说的是？- 没有 我只是…
- You were saying? - No, I was just…
很好 如我想听挖苦的话找我的孩子就行了 多谢
Good. Because if I want sarcasm, Mr. Tanner, I'll talk to my children.
- 晚安 007 - 晚安 M
- Good evening, 007. - Good evening, M.
首相在等最新报告
The Prime Minister's waiting for an update.
请开始简报 丹诺先生
Proceed with your briefing, Mr. Tanner.
谢谢
Thank you.
求救讯号后直升机就起飞
After the distress signal, your helicopter took off…
俄军派三架米格机拦截
and the Russians scrambled these three MIGs here to intercept it.
俄国人用这基地做什么？
What do you think the Russians are using the base for?
目前我们怀疑那也许是…
Well, at one point we suspected Severnaya might be the ground station…
…秘密太空武器“黄金眼”计划的基地
for a secret space-based weapons program called GoldenEye, but.
我们的分析显示对方既无财力…
Our statistical analysis saw they had…
也无技术力量运作
neither the finance nor technology to implement it.
我毫无数字观念
Numbers were never my strong suit.
这些图片是立即传送的？
Are these pictures live?
我们和美国政府不一样 不喜欢从CNN上得到坏消息
Unlike the American government, we prefer not to get our bad news from CNN.
目前并无异状 一切正常
Negative so far. Everything seems normal.
这到底是怎么搞的？
What the bloody hell was that?
娜坦雅席蒙娜
Natalya Fyodorovna Simonova.
Natalya Fyodorovna Simonova!
波洛！
Boris!
谢谢
Thanks.
我们的卫星被破坏了
Our satellite is knocked out.
另外两枚美国的也是
So are two of the Americans.
我们还有另一枚正在进入轨道
We have another coming into range…
现在正在传送影像
now.
老天！
Good God.
两架米格机坠毁
Two of the MIGs are down.
第三架撞到卫星天线
And it looks like the third went into the dish.
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
没有灯光
No lights.
方圆三十里内全部停电
Not one single electric light on in a 30-mile radius.
电磁波？
E.M.P.?
- 会引起米格机和卫星天线被毁 - 还有停电？
- That explains the MIGs and satellites. - And the blackout.
电磁波
Electromagnetic Pulse:
是一项美苏两国在冷战中…
A first-strike satellite weapon developed by the…
研发的攻击性卫星
The Americans and Soviets during the Cold War.
我看过简报 广岛核爆后发现的
I've read the brief. Discovered after Hiroshima.
在高层大气进行核爆
Set off a nuclear device in the upper atmosphere.
会产生激波
Creates a pulse…
极具毁灭性的辐射电流
a radiation surge that destroys everything with an electronic circuit.
在敌方反击前
The idea being to knock out the enemy's communications…
中断对方通讯
before he, she, or they could retaliate.
所以黄金眼确实存在
So, GoldenEye exists.
没错
Yes.
- 这是意外吗？- 不是
- Could this be an accident? - No.
因为直升机遭窃
The helicopter.
那是运送黄金眼的最好工具
If you wanted to steal the GoldenEye, it was the perfect getaway vehicle.
把基地炸掉就能毁灭证据
Setting off the blast was the ideal way to wipe out any trace of the crime.
亚努一伙？
The Janus group?
可能跟直升机有关
It may have been involved with the helicopter.
我知道俄国的安全措拖
I know the Russian failsafe systems.
你不能随便进去取得炸弹的钥匙
You don't just walk in and ask for the keys to the bomb.
必须要有密码
You need the access codes.
一定是有内贼
It had to be an insider.
至少有一个人知道是谁
And at least one person probably knows who it is.
非常好 谢谢 晚安
Very well, sir. Thank you. Good night.
首相与莫斯科联络过
The Prime Minister's talked to Moscow.
他们说例行演习出了意外
They're saying it was an accident during a routine training exercise.
换了政府还是照样说谎
Governments change. The lies stay the same.
亚努帮有线索吗？
What else do we know about the Janus syndicate?
军火商大本营在圣彼得堡
Topflight arms dealers, headquartered in St. petersburg.
波斯湾战争中提供伊拉克军火
The first outfit to restock the Iraqis during the Gulf War.
首脑身分不明 没有照片
The head man's unreliably described. No photographs.
那女人…安娜拓
The woman, Onatopp…
…是唯一的线索
is our only confirmed contact.
- 你要来杯酒吗？- 谢谢
- Would you care for a drink? - Thank you.
- 你的前任留下的干邑酒在上面… - 我喜欢波本酒
- Your predecessor kept cognac in the… - I prefer bourbon.
- 加冰吗？- 好的
- Ice? - Yes.
我们已经调阅了在塞维亚每个能获得
We've pulled the files on anyone who might have had access…
使用密码的人的档案
or authority at Severnaya.
据我所知 榜首是你的老朋友
The top name on the list is an old friend of yours, I understand.
巫洛莫
Ourumov.
他晋升了将军
They made him a General.
自以为是俄国下一位铁腕人物
He sees himself as the next Iron Man of Russia.
分析家认为他不可能叛国 他不在嫌疑犯名单上
So our political analysts rule him out He doesn't fit the profile of a traitor.
也是这些分析家说黄金眼是不可能存在的吗？
Are these the same analysts who said that GoldenEye couldn't exist?
他们还说直升机事件没有威胁
Who said the helicopter posed no immediate threat…
不值得调查？
and wasn't worth following?
邦德 你不喜欢我 你也不喜欢我的做法
You don't like me, Bond. You don't like my methods.
你认为我是会计
You think I'm an accountant…
做为会计 我更相信数据而不是你的直觉
a "bean counter, " more interested in my numbers than your instincts.
- 我是这么想过 - 很好
- The thought had occurred to me. - Good.
因为我觉得你是个歧视女人厌恶女人的恐龙
Because I think you're a sexist, misogynist dinosaur.
一个冷战的遗留人物 他那男孩的魅力…
A relic of the Cold War…
尽管对我不管用
whose boyish charms, though wasted on me, obviously appeal…
却迷倒了我派去评估你的少女
to that young woman I sent out to evaluate you.
- 我懂了 - 不完全 007
- Point taken. - Not quite, 007.
若你觉得我不敢派人送死
If you think for one moment I don't have the balls to send a man out to die…
你可就大错特错了
your instincts are dead wrong.
派你送死我心安理得
I've no compunction about sending you to your death.
但我不会轻举妄动 即使你以骑士的态度面对人生
But I won't do it on a whim, even with your cavalier attitude towards life.
我要你找到黄金眼
I want you to find GoldenEye.
找出谁是主犯阴谋是什么并且加以阻止
Find who took it, what they plan to do with it, and stop it.
如是遇到巫洛莫不管有没有罪…
And if you should come across Ourumov, guilty or not…
遇上他千万别公报私仇
I don't want you running off on some kind of vendetta.
为艾力克报仇也救不活他
Avenging Alec Trevelyan will not bring him back.
- 不是你让他害死的 - 也不是你杀的他
- You didn't get him killed. - Neither did you.
这点你不必自责
Don't make it personal.
不会的
Never.
邦德？
Bond.
活着回来
Come back alive.
（苏联 圣彼得堡）
早 巫将车
Good morning, General Ourumov.
国防部长米西根 各位好
Defense Minister Mishkin, gentlemen.
请开始报告
Please deliver your report.
据各位所知 一个秘密武器别号黄金眼…
As this Council is aware, 72 hours ago…
…在72小时前在塞维亚遭到引爆
a secret weapon system code-named GoldenEye was detonated over Severnaya.
作为太空部负责人
As head of Space Division…
我会亲自调查
I personally undertook the investigation.
我认为这个罪行是西伯利亚分裂主义者所为
I have concluded this crime was committed by Siberian separatists…
希望造成政治动乱
seeking to create political unrest.
很不幸…
Regrettably, the peaceful work…
塞维亚的太平的工作与外汇收入…
and much-needed hard currency earnings of Severnaya…
…不得不倒退几年
have been set back by several years.
在此我愿引咎辞职
Therefore, I tender my resignation.
委员会不想拿你开刀
It seems the Council does not want your head, Arkady Grigorovich.
只要你保证不会再有其他的金眼睛卫星武器
Merely your loyal assurance that there are no other GoldenEye satellites.
我向你保证 国防部长
I can give you that assurance, Defense Minister.
那失踪的两名技术员呢？
And what of the two missing Severnaya technicians?
我只知道一名 葛波洛
I was aware only of the one, Boris Grishenko.
还有一名女孩没找到尸体
There was a girl also whose body was not among the dead.
娜坦雅席蒙娜 二级程式设计师
Natalya Fyodorovna Simonova, a level-two programmer.
我会马上调查
I will investigate immediately, Defense Minister.
在你手下下落不明前
It would seem presumptuous, General…
断然指责…
to blame this incident on Siberian separatists…
西伯利亚分裂者不太好
before the whereabouts of your own people are determined.
不是吗？
Do you agree?
是的 部长
Yes, Defense Minister.
谢谢你提醒我
Thank you for bringing it to my attention.
没事了
That will be all.
早安 Q 腿怎么了？滑雪跌伤？
Morning, Q. Sorry about the leg. Skiing?
打猎
Hunting!
注意 007
Right. Now pay attention, 007.
你的车 宝马
First, your new car, BMW.
五段排档全方向雷达
Agile, five forward gears, all-points radar…
自动毁灭系统
self-destruct system…
各种设备齐全
and naturally, all the usual refinements.
我对这个特别感到骄傲
Now, this I'm particularly proud of.
车灯后面 刺螯飞弹
Behind the headlights, stinger missiles.
太好了 辛苦工作了一天 可以发泄一下
Excellent. Just the thing for unwinding after a rough day at the office.
我要提醒你 007
Need I remind you, 007…
虽然你有杀人执照…
that you have a licence to kill…
但开车还是不能违规
not to break the traffic laws.
- 我怎么敢 - 很好
- I wouldn't think of it. - Good.
现在来点实用知识
Right. Let's get on to more practical matters.
普通男用皮带
A typical leather belt.
三十四寸 扣环式
Male, size 34, buckle notch.
- 玩完了没？- 好了
- Have you finished? - Yes.
很好 普通皮带
Good. A typical leather belt.
这玩意我很熟
Q, I'm familiar with that device.
皮带扣藏有75尺钢丝
Not one with a 75-foot rappelling cord built into the buckle.
它能射出铁勾
Fire, and out shoots a piton…
加上强韧钢丝支撑你的重量
followed by a high-tensile wire designed to support your weight.
要是我要载人呢？
I see. And what if I need additional support?
只能一个人用 007
It's tested for one, 007.
878班机到圣彼得堡
Flight 878 to St. petersburg.
X光文件扫描器
X-ray document scanner.
笔 这是一只四级手榴弹
A pen. This is a Class Four grenade.
按三次后四秒引爆
Three clicks arms the four-second fuse.
马上再按三次就取消
Another three disarms it.
你说时间多久？
How long did you say the fuse was?
别玩了 007！
Oh, grow up, 007!
大家都说笔比剑更可怕
They always said the pen was mightier than the sword.
因为我 此话成真
Thanks to me, they were right.
咱们请费迪示范一次
Look, let's ask Freddie here to demonstrate for us.
对不起 费迪
Here we are. Sorry about this, Fred.
一 二 三
One… two… three.
别多嘴！
Don't say it.
墙上的涂鸦？
The writing's on the wall?
还有他的残舷
Along with the rest of him.
请你试着让这些装备
Now, 007, do please try and return some of…
完璧归赵
Do please try and return some of this equipment in pristine order.
别碰那个！那是我的午餐
Don't touch that! It's my lunch.
伦敦四月是春天
In London, April's a spring month.
是吗？你在报导气象吗？
Oh, yeah? And what are you, the weatherman?
拜托 另一个有密码和口令…
For crying out loud, another stiff-assed Brit…
…的英国佬
with your secret codes and your passwords.
总有一天 你们得学学别用这套
One of these days you guys are going to learn just to drop it.
算了吧 我的车在那儿
Come on, my car's over there.
- 你先请 - 谢谢
- After you. - Thank you.
就像你说的 别来这套
Like you said, drop it.
好 在伦敦四月是春天
In London, April's a spring month…
圣彼得堡却冷得要命
whereas in St. petersburg we're freezing our butts off!
这样够了吗？
Now, is that close enough for government work?
不够 给我看玫瑰
No. Show me the rose.
饶了我吧
Please, no.
好吧 好吧！
All right, all right, all right!
- “小毛”？- 我第三个老婆
- "Muffy"? - Third wife.
- 我是中情局魏杰克 - 英国佬 詹姆斯邦德
- Jack Wade, CIA. - James Bond, stiff-assed Brit.
- 身手不错 - 你的车也不错
- That's a nice move. - Nice car.
这个宝贝还没抛过锚呢
This baby hasn't let me down yet.
不中看却很中用
She's an ugly little bitch, but she gets you there.
嘿 邦德？你种花吗？
Hey, Bond, you do any gardening?
吉米 把钳子拿给我
Hand me that wrench, Jimmy?
- 你对亚努了解多少？- 一无所知
- What do you know about Janus? - Zilch. Zipsky.
没人见过他 但他有高官相护
No one's ever seen him. But the man's connected up the kazoo.
KGB 军方螺丝起子
KGB, military. Screwdriver.
听说他住在旧苏联飞弹列车上
Rumor has it, he lives on one of those old Soviet missile trains…
包着铁甲到处开 所以我们无法追踪
that armored stuff they ran around the country so we couldn't target them.
把鎚子给我好吗？
Want to hand me that hammer, Jimbo?
不 大的那个
No, the bigger one. The sledge.
老实说 你找不到这家伙 只有他找得到你
Anyways, to tell the truth, you don't find this guy. He finds you.
哼 不都是一些俄国黑手党
Hell, it's all Russian Mafia.
我只能带你找他的对手
The best thing I can do is point you in the direction of his competition.
- 这个对手是谁？- 前KGB的人 凶汉
- Who is the competition? - An ex-KGB guy.
右脚瘸了 叫祖考斯基
A tough mother. Got a limp on his right leg. Name's Zukovsky.
- 维伦汀祖考斯基？- 对呀 你认识他？
- Valentin Dimitreveych Zukovsky? - Yeah. You know him?
他是被我打跛的
I gave him the limp.
是吗？
Yes?
只有这些吗？
Are these all you have?
你还要多少？
How many do you want?
美国学校24台 瑞典11台
Twenty-four for the American school, eleven for the Swedish.
IBM相容 五百MG硬碟
IBM compatible with 500 meg. hard drives…
附光碟机和数据机
CD ROM and 14.4 modems.
- 付美金吗？- 当然了
- Will you pay dollars? - Of course.
若女士需要 我可以演示…
If madame would require a demonstration, I could…
我要一个样品到安静的地方试用
Madame requires one demonstration model and a quiet place to test it.
（电子邮件接收）
娜坦雅
Natalya.
（我以为你死了）
（巫将车大开杀戒发射卫星武器 取走黄金眼）
一切都满意吗？
Is everything satisfactory?
不被你打搅扰很好
Everything except the interruption.
（你很危险 别信任别人）
（一小时后教堂见）
让我弄清楚 吉米
Now let me get you straight, Jimmy.
你射伤了他的脚偷走他的车和女友
You shot him in the leg, you stole his car, you took his girl.
现在却要他帮你和亚努见面？
And now you want Valentin Zukovsky to set you up with Janus?
是的
Yes.
你想干什么？你想打动他的心吗？
Well, what are you going to do? Appeal to his heart?
不 他的钱包
No, his wallet.
啊 这可能有用 好啦 好戏上场
Oh, that might work. Okay, show time.
大本营在23大楼
Valentin operates out of building number 23 there.
你真的要这么做吗？
Are you sure you want to do this?
上次有人硬闯 结果被化成灰…
Last guy who dropped in uninvited went home airfreight…
…装在小盒子送上飞机
in very small boxes.
我一定要坐头等舱
Make sure they send me home first-class.
娜坦雅！是我 波洛！
Natalya, it's me! It's Boris!
波洛！波洛！
It's Boris! It's Boris! Hello.
今天倒霉透顶
Another morning shot to hell.
自由市场经济会害死我
Free market economy. I swear it will be the end of me.
PPK 7.65口径
Walther PPK, 7.65 millimeter.
我知道只有三个人用这种枪
Only three men I know use such a gun.
我知道我杀了两个
I believe I've killed two of them.
算我走运
Lucky me.
不见得
I think not.
詹姆斯邦德
James Bond.
魅力十足的情报员
Charming, sophisticated secret agent.
处变不惊
Shaken but not stirred.
你的幽默感还在 维伦汀
I see you haven't lost your delicate sense of humor, Valentin, huh?
还是需要观众
Or your need for an audience.
谁唱歌像鸡叫？
Who's strangling the cat?
像鸡叫？
Strangling a cat?
爱琳娜 我的情妇
That is Irina, my mistress.
挺有才华的女郎
A very talented girl.
爱琳娜！给我滚！
Irina! Take a hike!
那么 邦德先生
So, Mr. Bond…
什么风把你吹来当邻居？
what is it that brings you to my neighborhood, hmm?
还替老掉牙的情报局做事呢？
Still working for MI6…
还是跨入21世纪了？
or have you decided to join the 21st century?
听说新M是个女的
I hear the new M is a lady.
我要你帮个忙
I want you to do me a favor.
他要我帮个忙！
He wants me to do him a favor!
我的膝盖…
My knee aches…
每天都痛 冬天更痛
every single day, twice as bad when it is cold.
你知道苏俄冬天有多长吗？
Have you any idea how long the winter lasts in this country, hmm?
告诉他 老弟！
Tell him, Dimitri!
- 这个么 要看… - 闭嘴！
- Well, it depends… - Silence!
你这过去的KGB干员 你让我吃惊啊 老兄
For an ex-KGB agent, you surprise me, Valentin.
我不是故意射你膝盖
Someone of your stature must've realized the skill was not to hit your knee…
而是饶你老命
but to… miss the rest of you.
你为什么饶我？
So why did you not kill me?
算是职业上的礼貌
Call it professional courtesy.
那我还得报答你
Then I should extend you the same courtesy.
下午四点契氏殡仪馆
Kirov's funeral parlor, 4:00 this afternoon.
棺材藏有两百磅强力炸药
Two hundred pounds of C4 explosives hidden in a casket.
你手下把棺材载去换钱
Your man drives the hearse in, the money's exchanged…
对方把棺材接走
their man drives the hearse out.
结果他们因炸药被逮捕
Their man will be arrested with the explosives.
你们的人就能带着你的钱奇迹式脱身
Your man will make a miraculous escape with the money.
你的钱
Your money.
我用什么跟你交换？
And what do I owe for this accommodation?
我要你安排我和亚努见面
I want you to set me up… with Janus.
他怎么会惹上你？
What has he done to deserve you?
- 他偷了架直升机 - 我有六架
- Stole a helicopter. - I have six.
三架 其他的不能飞
Three. None that fly.
谁管它？
Who's counting?
这些人是卖国贼
These are not just criminals, Valentin, they're traitors.
他们偷走核武
They used the chopper to steal a nuclear weapon.
滥投俄国无辜
Killed a lot of innocent Russians doing it.
- 哥萨克人本性 - 谁？
- What do you expect from a Cossack? - Who?
我是说亚努 我没见过他 可我知道他是哥萨克人
This Janus, I've never met the man, but I know he's a Lienz Cossack.
二次大战与纳粹合作对抗俄国
Group that worked for the Nazis against the Russians, Second World War.
你懂历史嘛 战争结束后…
You know your history, Mr. Bond. At the end of the war…
哥萨克人向奥地利的英军投降…
the Lienz Cossacks surrendered to the British in Austria…
…以为能和英军对抗俄共
believing they'd join your government and wage war against the communists.
但是被英国人出卖了
But, the British betrayed them…
送回苏联后被斯大林下令处死
sent them promptly back to Stalin who promptly had them all shot…
老弱妇孺
women, children, families.
不是我们的光荣时刻
Not exactly our finest hour.
他们很残暴 死了活该
Still, ruthless people. They got what they deserved.
我要你安排我见亚努 跟他提直升机的事
I want you to set me up with Janus. Tell him I'm asking about the chopper.
今晚在欧洲大饭店碰面
You're going to meet me tonight at the Grand Hotel Europe.
我们俩就扯平了 那么他却欠我个人情？
And then, you and I are even and he owes me one?
没错
Precisely.
中校 你不需要用枪
You don't need the gun, Commander.
这要看你的安全做爱的定义是什么
That depends on your definition of "safe sex."
那就够近的了
That's close enough.
我可不这么想
Not for what I have in mind.
你能伤得了我？
Oh, you think you can hurt me?
你能驯服我吗？
You think you can break me?
嗯！嗯！
Yes! Yes!
嗯！
Yes!
不 不 不！
No, no, no.
不要前戏了
No more foreplay.
带我见亚努
Take me to Janus.
- 就是这个？- 对
- This is it? - Yes.
那么 我必须说…我有个愉快的夜晚 你呢？
Well, I must say, I've had a lovely evening. You?
这次又是你的荣幸
Well, once again, the pleasure was all yours.
别怪我不跟你联络
You'll understand if I don't call.
我不会睡不着觉
I won't lose sleep over it.
那就做个好梦吧
Sweet dreams.
嗨 詹姆斯
Hello, James.
- 艾力克？- 死人复活了
- Alec? - Back from the dead.
不再是情报局纪念墙上的无名氏
No longer just an anonymous star on the memorial wall at MI6.
怎么了？不是开玩笑？
What's the matter, James? No glib remark?
不反言相讥？
No pithy comeback?
为什么？
Why?
你这问题真可笑
Hilarious question, particularly from you.
你问过为什么吗？
Did you ever ask why?
为何要努力推翻暴政强权？
Why we toppled all those dictators, undermined all those regimes?
回国被褒扬一番
Only to come home: "Well done, good job. But sorry, old boy.
然后发现生活全变了
Everything you risked your life and limb for has changed."
- 这是我们的选择 - 你一定会这么说
- It was the job we were chosen for. - Of course you'd say that.
詹姆斯邦德 女王的忠犬
James Bond, Her Majesty's loyal terrier…
捍卫所谓的“信仰”
defender of the so-called "faith."
拜托啦 詹姆斯 把枪拿开
Oh, please, James, put it away.
你每一步都在我意料之中
It's insulting to think I haven't anticipated your every move.
没错
Yes.
- 我信任你 艾力克 - 信任？
- I trusted you, Alec. - Trust?
真好笑
What a quaint idea.
为什么情报局没发觉你父母是哥萨克人
How did the MI6 screening miss that your parents were Lienz Cossacks?
你又错了 他们知道
Once again, your faith is misplaced. They knew.
我们都是孤儿
We're both orphans, James.
你的父母有幸死于山难
But where your parents had the luxury of dying in a climbing accident…
我父母逃过英人的背叛和斯大林的毒手
mine survived the British betrayal and Stalin's execution squads.
我父亲却不愿他们自己活在耻辱中
But my father couldn't let himself, or my mother, live with the shame of it.
情报局以为我太小不记得
MI6 figured I was too young to remember.
而人生却少有的讽刺
And in one of life's little ironies…
父母被英国出卖决定自尽
the son went to work for the government whose betrayal…
儿子却为这国家工作
caused the father to kill himself and his wife.
你才会变成亚努
Hence, Janus.
双面的罗马门神
The two-faced Roman god come to life.
这脸非上帝造成 是拜你所赐
It wasn't God who gave me this face, it was you…
把炸弹设定三分钟而不是六分钟
setting the timers for three minutes instead of six.
我该同情你吗？
Am I supposed to feel sorry for you?
不 你该为我而死
No. You're supposed to die for me.
对了…
Oh, by the way…
…我本想邀你参加我的小计划
I did think of asking you to join my little scheme…
不过我知道…
but somehow I knew…
007永远把任务摆在朋友之前
007's loyalty was always to the mission, never to his friend.
散场了 最后通知
Closing time, James. Last call.
为了英国 醒醒
For England, James.
先生！
Mister!
醒醒！拜托！
Wake up, please!
- 醒醒！- 我在这儿
- Wake up! - I'm here.
- 我在这儿！- 快！
- I'm here! - Hurry!
赶快！
Hurry up! Come out!
振作点 我们快死了！
Pull yourself together! We're going to die!
想个办法 从这出去！
Do something! Get us out of here!
我被绑住了 算了吧
I'm a little tied up Never mind.
（发射时间）
（发射）
（目标）
（紧急跳出）
收集飞机里程数还真辛苦
The things that we do for "frequent flyer" mileage.
让我帮你一把
Here, let me help you.
就这样 小心头
That's it, mind your head.
放开我！
Let me go!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我和你是一伙 来帮你的
Listen, I'm on your side. I'm here to help you.
- 我什么都不知道…- 我不相信你
- I don't know anything. - I don't believe you.
- 我不在乎 - 瞧！
- I don't care what you believe. - Look!
他们随时都会回来 你要么趁机跟我走…
They might be back for us any minute. You either take your chances with me…
或者跟随塞维亚杀人屠夫
or your fellow countrymen who killed everyone at Severnaya.
我从没去过塞维亚
I've never been to Severnaya.
你的表去过 在金眼睛爆炸中停了
Your watch has. Frozen by the GoldenEye blast.
你猜你一定是爬上接收盘后逃出来的女孩
And I'm willing to bet you're the one who climbed up the dish to get out.
- 你是谁？- 我替英国政府做事
- Who are you? - I work for the British government.
你说的越多我就越有办法帮你
And the more you tell me, the more I can help you.
- 但我什么都不知道 - 从你知道的开始说吧
- But I don't know anything! - Then let's start with what you do know.
我叫娜坦雅
My name is Natalya Simonova.
塞维亚的程式设计师
I was a systems programmer at Severnaya facility until.
说下去
Go on.
- 直到他们杀死了所有人 - 谁？艾力克？
- Until they killed everyone. - Who? Alec Trevelyan?
我不认识他
No. I don't know who that is.
谁是内贼？叛徒？
Who was the insider? Who was the traitor?
葛波洛
Boris. Boris Grishenko.
- KGB还是军方？- 电脑程式设计师
- KGB or military? - Computer programmer.
- 没别人了吗？- 没有
- There was no one else? - No.
他们会杀我
They're going to kill me, aren't they?
相信我
Trust me.
相信你？我连你叫什么都不知道
Trust you? I don't even know your name.
早 邦德先生
Good morning, Mr. Bond.
坐吧
Sit.
我是国防部长 米西根
I'm Defense Minister Dimitri Mishkin.
我们该怎么处决你 邦德先生？
So, by what means shall we execute you, Commander Bond?
什么？不先聊聊吗？
What, no small talk?
不打屁一下？现在的人都不懂得严刑拷打
No chitchat? That's the trouble with the world today.
这是个失传的艺术
No one takes the time to do a sinister interrogation anymore. It's a lost art.
我并不欣赏你的幽默
Your sense of humor doesn't slay me, Commander. I'm sorry.
- 黄金眼在哪里？- 你没有吗？
- Where is the GoldenEye? - I assumed you had it.
我有英国间谍 塞维亚人程式设计师和直升机…
I have an English spy, a Severnaya programmer and the helicopter they took.
贵国叛徒想要的…
That's what some traitor in your government wanted it to look like.
- 谁背后指使你攻击？- 谁有在弄权…
- Who was behind the attack on Severnaya? - Who had the authorization codes?
恐怖份子还是死罪
Russia may have changed, but the penalty for terrorism is still death!
- 叛国罪呢？- 你们俩都住口！闭嘴！
- And what's the penalty for treason? - Stop it, both of you! Stop it!
你们简直就像小孩子抢玩具
You're like boys with toys.
是巫洛莫 是他发射武器
It was Ourumov. General Ourumov set off the weapon.
我亲眼目睹
I saw him do it.
你确定吗？
Are you certain it was Ourumov?
他杀死了每个人 还偷走了黄金眼
Yes. He killed everyone and stole the GoldenEye.
他为什么这么做？
And why would he do that?
还有另一枚卫星
There is another satellite.
另一颗黄金眼
Another GoldenEye?
谢谢你 席小姐
Thank you, Miss Simonova.
你是说严刑拷打失传了
You were saying something about the lost art of interrogation, Mr. Bond?
部长 我要抗议！
Defense Minister, I must protest!
此案由我调查 你太过分了
This is my investigation. You are out of order.
据我所知 你才过分
From what I am hearing, it is you who's out of order!
- 我见过这把枪 - 把枪放下
- I have seen this gun before. - Put it down.
- 跟我们的敌人共处 - 把枪放下！
- In the hand of our enemy. - Put it down, General!
你知道敌人是谁吗？
Do you even know who the enemy is, Dimitri?
- 你知道吗？- 警卫！
- Do you? - Guard!
国防部长
Defense Minister Dimitri Mishkin…
被英国情报员詹姆斯邦德杀害了
murdered by a British agent, James Bond.
他逃亡时也遭到射杀 警卫！
Himself shot while trying to escape. Guards!
来呀！
Come on!
他们在档案室！
They're in the archives!
下面！
Down!
另外一边！
Spread out! Cover the other side!
相信我
Trust me.
快走！
Go now!
快点！
Faster!
可恶！
Damn it!
开进巷子！
Down the alley!
快撞上去！
Use the bumper! That's what it's for!
那是什么？
What was that?
左转！
Go left!
出来！
Get out!
若你没带来大礼
Either you've brought me the perfect gift, General Ourumov…
你就会让我很生气
or you've made me a very unhappy man.
米西根捷足先登
Mishkin got to them before I could.
邦德还活着？
Bond is alive?
他逃走了
He escaped.
邦德得意了 你就糟糕了
Good for Bond. Bad for you.
坐下来吧 亲爱的
Take a seat, my dear.
我和詹姆斯无话不谈
You know, James and I shared everything.
绝对是无话不谈
Absolutely everything.
胜者为王
To the victor go the spoils.
你会喜欢我们要去的地方
You'll like it where we're going.
你可能还会喜欢我
You may even learn to like me.
看住她
Stay with her.
邦德
Bond.
一定是邦德
Only Bond.
他要让我们出轨
He's going to derail us.
全速前进！
Full speed!
全速前进！撞死他！
Full speed! Ram him!
你为何不乖乖去死？
Why can't you just be a good boy and die?
你先死
You first.
你是下一个
You… second.
举起来！
Up!
情况看来 陷入绝境了
Situation analysis: hopeless.
你没有后援 也没退路
You have no backup, no escape route.
而找还有一个筹码
And I have the only bargaining chip.
她人呢？
Where is she?
你致命的弱点
Oh, yes. Your fatal weakness.
巫洛莫 带她进来
Ourumov, bring her in.
漂亮妞
Lovely girl.
尝起来就…像草莓
Tastes like… Iike strawberries.
- 我可不知道 - 我知道
- I wouldn't know. - I would.
重回原点啦
So, back where we started, James.
为朋友还是为使命？
Your friend or the mission.
把枪放下 我就不杀她
Drop the gun. I'll let her live.
巫洛莫 他答应你什么了？
Ourumov, what has this Cossack promised you?
你知道 对不对？他是哥萨克人
You knew, didn't you? He's a Lienz Cossack.
- 都过去了 - 他会背叛你！
- It's in the past. - He'll betray you!
- 就跟别人一样 - 是真的吗？
- Just like everyone else. - Is this true?
事实是48小时后我们会比上帝还有钱
What's true is that in 48 hours you and I will have more money than God.
这里将为邦德先生开个小小的葬礼
And Mr. Bond here will have a small memorial service…
只有钱班霓小姐和几个酒肉朋友会去
with only Moneypenny and a few tearful restaurateurs in attendance.
所以 你打算怎么办 詹姆斯？
So, what's the choice, James?
两个目标 时间只能射一个
Two targets. Time enough for one shot.
女孩 还是使命？
The girl, or the mission?
杀了她 她对我无任何意义
Kill her. She means nothing to me.
地狱见吧 詹姆斯
See you in hell, James.
一寸厚铁甲
One-inch armor plating.
我没事 谢谢你
I'm fine, thank you very much!
- 波洛 太好了！- 你在干嘛？
- Boris, yes! - What are you doing?
波洛在线上
Boris is on-line, backing up his files.
我能找出他们的去处
If I can spike him, I might be able to find out where they're going.
别光站在那儿！设法让我们逃生！
But don't stand there! Get us out of here!
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
祝你好运 詹姆斯
Good luck with the floor, James.
我设定时炸弹到六分钟引爆 跟你给我的六分钟一样
I set the timers for six minutes, the same six minutes you gave me.
这是我至少能对朋友做到的
It was the least I could do for a friend.
- 他什么意思？- 我们只有三分钟
- What does that mean? - We've got three minutes.
（通讯中断 请传送破坏讯号）
（破坏讯号已传送）
（输入密码 屁股和臀部）
（无效）
屁股还叫什么？
What else do you call your butt?
- 什么？- 波洛的密码
- What? - It's Boris' password.
“什么是能坐却不能带走？”
He plays word games: "What I sit on, but I don't take it with me."
- 椅子 - 我说过
- Chair. - Like I said.
（椅子 开始搜寻）
剩三十秒
Thirty seconds.
不在俄国 德国 巴黎 伦敦 马德里
He's not in Russia, Germany, Paris, London, Madrid.
二十五秒
Twenty-five seconds.
…纽约 多伦多 芝加哥 旧金山…
New York, Toronto, Chicago, San Francisco.
二十秒！
Twenty seconds!
墨西哥市 里约 迈阿密
Mexico City, Rio, Miami.
- 快点呀！- 等等！
- Come on! - Wait!
他在古巴 哈瓦那 不
He's in Cuba, Havana. No.
（断线）
现在！
Now!
你都破坏你所有乘坐的交通工具？
Do you destroy every vehicle you get into?
标准操作程序
Standard operating procedure.
有玩具的男孩
"Boys with toys."
也许我该安排一下到古巴的交通工具
Maybe I should take care of the transportation for our trip to Cuba.
去古巴？
Our trip?
你会拆除卫星武器吗？
Do you know how to disarm the weapon?
这要看你说是哪种武器
I suppose that depends on what kind of weapon you're talking about disarming.
那么 告诉我
So, tell me.
…还有其他别的什么“标准操作过程”…
Are there any other standard operating procedures…
我应该知道的 中校？
I should be aware of, Commander?
数不完
Thousands.
但是都只是…
But I only pay them…
嘴上说说而已
Iip service.
我一生都梦想到加勒比海
My whole life, I dreamed about coming to the Caribbean.
真美极了
It's so beautiful.
漫无人迹
Not another human being in sight.
你跟交通工具犯冲吗？
What is it with you and moving vehicles?
嗨 老詹！
Yo, Jimbo!
那老头叫我带个礼物给你
Brought a little gift from old what's-his-name, uh, T, Z?
- Q - 对
- Q. - Yeah.
- 你来干嘛？- 榕树
- What are you doing here, Wade? - Banyan trees.
就算我没来
I am not here.
中情局不知情不干涉…
The CIA has no knowledge, no involvement, absolutely nothing to do…
你到古巴跟我们无关 懂吗？
with your insertion into Cuba, if you catch my drift.
懂 我很明白
Yes, I do, perfectly.
飞机是向缉毒组朋友借的
Borrowed the plane from a friend of mine in the DEA.
海岸防卫队知道此事
Now, the Coast Guard and the FAA are both in the loop.
你在我们的雷达上消失了六小时
You're cleared on our radar for 0600 hours.
上面有最新的探测仪器
Here's the latest Sat-Int from Langley.
- 保持六百尺以下 - 五百尺
- Stay below 600 feet. - 500 feet.
- 她是谁？- 娜坦雅席曼娜
- Who's that? - Natalya Siminova.
娜坦雅席米娜
Natalya Simonova.
俄国交通部长
Russian Minister of Transportation.
你查过她吗？
Did you check her out?
- 从头到脚 - 好啊
- Head to toe. - Right.
你要找的足球场大的卫星天线 根本没有
So, you're looking for a dish the size of a football field, huh?
在古巴什么事情也瞒不过我们
Doesn't exist. You can't light a cigar in Cuba without us seeing it.
我知道一定有 跟塞维亚的一样
I know it's there.
在你们在纽西兰的秘密发射器一样
It's a duplicate of Severnaya, like your secret transmitters in New Zealand.
我从没去过那 她怎么知道的？
I've never been to New Zealand. How'd she know about that?
我需要支援怎么办？
What if I need backup?
通过广播联络 我会派海军陆战队来
Get on the radio. I'll send in the Marines.
跑道尽头转左
Anyway, hang a left at the end of the runway.
- 古巴在右边八十英里 - 好啦 老魏！
- Cuba's 80 miles on your right. - Yo, Wade.
有一件事 别乱按车上的钮
Just one thing: Don't push any of the buttons on that car.
- 我只是兜兜风 - 是啊
- I was going to go bombing around in it. - Exactly.
詹姆斯 我有信心 但你要小心点 他知道你要来
Yo, James, I got faith. But be careful. He knows you're coming.
特维阳是你的朋友
He was your friend, Trevelyan?
现在他是你的敌人 你要杀死他
And now he's your enemy and you will kill him.
就这么简单
It is that simple?
也就是说 一点也没错
In a word, yes.
除非他先杀死你
Unless he kills you first.
- 娜坦雅… - 你以为我会有好印象？
- Natalya… - You think I'm impressed?
你们这些人只会拿枪杀人 为了什么？
All of you with your guns, your killing, your death. For what?
只是为了当个英雄吗？
So you can be a hero?
- 英雄难逃一死 - 听我说
- All the heroes I know are dead. - Natalya, listen to me.
你怎么能这么做？你怎么能这么冷酷无情？
How can you act like this? How can you be so cold?
这样才能活下去
It's what keeps me alive.
不！
No.
你才会这么孤独
It's what keeps you alone.
詹姆斯
James?
什么事？
Yes?
在火车上…
On the train…
你叫他杀我 还说我对你无意义
when you told him to kill me and I meant nothing to you…
你是真的吗？
did you mean it?
是的
Yes.
基本规则 一定要骗他们
Basic rule: always call their bluff.
不…
No.
往南十度 方位一八四
Turn ten degrees south, bearing one-eight-four.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
什么都没有 这里什么都没有
Nothing. There is nothing here.
再绕一次
Let's make another pass.
也许老魏是对的 什么都没有
Maybe Wade was right. There is no dish.
娜坦雅
Natalya.
邦德先生 这次 换我占到上风了
This time, Mr. Bond, the pleasure will be all mine.
等一下才到你
Wait for your turn.
她一向都喜欢这样
She always did enjoy a good squeeze.
卫星进入接收范围吗？
Is the satellite in range?
- 再过六分钟 - 开启接收天线
- Six minutes. - Prepare the dish.
不！太早 我还没好
No! It's too early. I am not ready.
开启
Do it!
难怪我们看不到
No wonder we couldn't see it.
来吧
Come on.
世上最好用的提款卡
The world's greatest cash card.
最好别被拒收
It had better not be rejected.
- 天线已开启 - 长官！
- Mischa is on-line. - Sir.
杀死他
Kill him!
他老是学不了乖
The man just won't take a hint.
- 目标座标 - 是伦敦
- Target coordinates? - The target is London.
他准备向卫星发出讯号
He's getting ready to signal the satellite.
- 怎么阻止他？- 天线上的发射器
- How do you stop it? - The transmitter above the antenna.
天线已就位
Antenna in position.
倒数
On my count.
三 二 一
Three… two… one.
（伦敦）
（武器准备就绪）
天佑女王
God save the Queen.
电脑主机
The mainframe computer.
别动
Don't move.
詹姆斯！真是意想不到啊
James! What an unpleasant surprise.
- 我的目标是取乐于你 - 那女孩呢？
- We aim to please. - Where's the girl?
把她找到！
Find her!
Q那老家伙好吗？
So, how is old Q?
还是他的老一套吗？
Up to his usual tricks?
手表
The watch.
新款式
A new model.
还是按这里吗？
Still press here, do I?
装配得挺有趣 艾立克
Interesting setup, Alec.
你侵入了英国银行电脑转帐…
You break into the Bank of England via computer…
…把钱用电脑转出
and then transfer the money electronically…
然后马上启动黄金眼
just seconds before you set off the GoldenEye…
毁灭一切证据
which erases any record of the transactions.
- 真高明 - 谢谢 詹姆斯
- Ingenious. - Thank you, James.
不过这是小偷的行为
But it still boils down to petty theft.
你最终也不过是个银行抢劫犯
In the end, you're just a bank robber.
跟个小偷差不多
Nothing more than a common thief.
（进行编列密码）
你眼光老是这么狭窄
You always did have a small mind, James.
我们不只销毁银行记录
It's not just erasing bank records.
而是毁灭全伦敦的电脑系统
It's everything on every computer in Greater London:
税捐记录 股市信用记录…土地登记
Tax records, the stock market, credit ratings, land registries…
犯罪记录
criminal records.
再过十六分钟又四十三秒
In 16 minutes and 43 sec…
不 四十二秒后英国将回到石器时代
No, 42 seconds, the United Kingdom will reenter the Stone Age.
全球金融瓦解
A worldwide financial meltdown.
疯狂的艾力克完成了五十年的凤愿
And all so mad little Alec can settle a score with the world 50 years on.
哦 拜托 詹姆斯别对我心理分析
Oh, please, James. Spare me the Freud.
杀人无数以后
I might as well ask you if all the vodka martinis ever silence the screams…
烈酒能让哀号宁静吗
of all the men you've killed.
你在那些女人怀中得到宽恕了吗？
Or if you find forgiveness in the arms of all those willing women…
对于所有那些你不能保护的死者
for all the dead ones you failed to protect.
英国将懂得背叛的代价
England is about to learn the cost of betrayal…
1945年的萧条
inflation-adjusted for 1945.
- 欢迎加入 亲爱的 - 娜坦雅！
- Welcome to the party, my dear. - Natalya!
别再这么做了！
Don't ever do that again!
你玩不起这游戏
This is not one of your games, Boris.
人真的会死 虫你这可怜
Real people will die! You pathetic little worm.
她在电脑主机上动过手脚 快查！
She was in the mainframe. Check the computer.
她这笨蛋 二流程式设计师
She's a moron. A second-level programmer.
她只处理过导航系统
She works on the guidance system.
她没有发射密码
She doesn't even have access to the firing codes.
制动火箭发射中
Retrorockets firing!
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell's happening?
卫星十二分钟后重返大气层
We will have reentry in… 12 minutes!
（任务取消）
- 会在大西洋某地上空烧毁 - 快处理！
- It will burn up over the Atlantic. - Deal with it!
她改了密码
She changed the access codes!
她可以改回来
Well, then she can fix it.
尽管杀他 杀了他 他对我无意义
Go ahead, shoot him. He means nothing to me.
我可以！
I can do it!
- 我可以破解她的密码！- 那么 快做！
- I can break her codes. - Then get on with it!
告诉他！快点！
Tell him, now!
把密码告诉我！告诉我！
Give me the codes, Natalya! Give them to me!
- 波洛能破解密码吗？- 有可能
- Can Boris break your codes? - Possibly.
有可能？
Possibly?
我们得摧毁发射器
We have to destroy the transmitter.
另外 我很好 谢谢关心
By the way, I'm fine, thank you very much.
你知道怎么用吗？
Do you know how to use one of these?
知道
Yes.
很好 躲起来
Good. Stay out of sight.
- 还剩多久？- 二分钟 一分钟
- How long? - Two minutes. One minute.
- 警卫！- 我正在做
- Guard! - I'm fixing it!
他敢溜就宰了他
If he moves, kill him.
（重新设定时间 08点23分）
我所向无敌！
Yes! I am invincible!
（天线重新定位）
（天线失效）
詹姆斯 你要知道…我一向比你强
You know, James… I was always better.
一号呼叫基地
Alpha One to Gunship.
一号呼叫基地！
Alpha One to Gunship!
说话！
Speak to me!
为了英国 詹姆斯？
For England, James?
不…
No.
…为了我
For me.
我所向无敌！
Yes! I am invincible!
詹姆斯！詹姆斯！
James! James!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我没事 谢谢
Yes, I'm fine, thank you.
要是被人看见怎么办？
Suppose someone is watching?
方圆25里内没人的 相信我
No. There's no one within 25 miles, believe me.
哟 老詹！
Yo, Jimbo!
你这算是及时解围吗？
Is this supposed to be your idea of, uh, coming through in a clinch?
烟草种植园 我说我会来的
It's tobacco plants. I said I'd be here, huh?
海军陆战队兄弟！
Yo! Marines!
你们不如到关塔那莫去继续互相亲热
Maybe you two would like to finish debriefing each other at Guantanamo.
- 可以吗？- 我不跟你坐直升机
- You ready? - I'm not going on a helicopter with you.
不跟你坐飞机或火车
No plane, no train, nothing that moves.
亲爱的 怎么会有声？
Darling, what could possible go wrong, eh?
[为了纪念德瑞克·莫丁斯]